Stop
别打了
"May 2002, Six months before Yan's death”
「2002年5月，陈永仁殉职前六个月。j
Know what "Screwed up" means?
知不知道什么叫侄 ?
The first masseuse came in
刚才那按摩小姐一进来
She looked like Sam's dog
样子就像琛哥的狗
So 1 asked for a replacement
我当然不要她
The new one Was worse
好 ' 第二个进来， 更精
She's the dead ringer of Sam
跟琛哥一模一样
Just imagine
你想想
1 simply couldn't swallow that
我再随便也受不了
She dared to ask if she's pretty
她还敢周我她漂不漂亮
Of course 1 said no
她敢问，我当然敢褒不
And she clawed me. So 1 called you
她就抓下来，我才急著传呼你
That's what's screwed up
过就倒相了
And you wrecked the whole place
你还毁了人家的店
That's gonna cost me a fortune
我现在要赔上夫万志
So ifa masseuse is ugly
所以说 ，遇上柄的按摩小姐
you're screwed
就一定倒大栏
How dare You swear at your boss?
堤嘛，竟敢用粗话需大哥?
Ouch
议士小组，还说不怎床痛
Yan
仁哥
Its asmall gig, Don't give me shit
我不过叫你做点事，你就发我脾气 ?
You bitch that 1 give you no work
过严年来，你老埋她汽事可做
But crooks don't need to work
出来混就是少做痪妙叮
上 you want work, why not be a cop?
你那床喜获做事，何不去投考警察 ?
Know why 1 only
你可知道我为什么
take you under my wing?
只有你一个手下, 仁哥?
Its because you're focused
汽别的，我就是喜葡你做事狗专心
lt pays to be focused, Look at Sam
做事专心很重要， 你看琛哥
He's so focused, no?
他做事多专必,是吧 ?
As for what happened today
还有，今天的事
Dont let Sam know
你可别告诉琛哥
After his wife died
自从大嫂死后
he hates us horsing around
他最讨屎我们去史混
Gimme a break, would ya?
你放过我吧
Are you done talking? Go inside
说狗没有 ，” 走吧
Hey, stop pushing me, officer
别推我呀 ，警官
One shouldn't be like that. Youre a cop
做人不是运样的，做警察也不是过样的
So are you gonna tell on me?
怎床样，你府不说 ?
Enough
角了
So are you gonna tell on me?
那你到底襄不说 ?
Go to hell
去你的
Cut it out
别打
How dare you beat up your boss?
打大哥 ? 你怎厅能打大哥
"October 2003. Ten months after Yan's death”
12003年10月，陈永仁殉职后十个月。j
File number ID143
档案篇号I0143
Regarding the deaths of ofcer Yan
有关DPC27149陈永仁
and officer Billy
及DPC34689林国平殉职案件
IA has made the following report
内藉部烃过莘查作出以下报告
On November 26, 2002
2002年11月26日
Sr. Inspector Ming of IA
内藉部高级督察刘建明
contacted undercover officer Yan
联络欧底警员陈永仁
Tipped off by Yan
兹根据陈警员提供和线报
Ming toppled Sam's drug operation
联同西九龙有和组织及忆重罪案调查科
together with the OCTB unit in West Kowloon
破获圭琛晨毒集团
$60 million worth of cocaine was seized
起出价值六干万毒品可卡因
On November 27, 2002
2002年11月27日
Ming met with Yan again
陈警员於港篇区四方商业大广天台
onthe rooftop of FSC Center
再狗见刘警官
Yan supplied intel on triad moles
提供有关警方内奸的牧索
You can't get away
你跑不了的
Just wait and see
So youre planning to whack a cop?
庚道你想欠和警察 ?
1 know all about you and Sam
你和埋琛的事我全知道
Youve no choice. Come back with me
你汉得玩择 ，跟我回去
Drop your gun
把检放下
What are you planning to do?
你到底想怎样 ?
1just wanna get away
我想走
The foregoing testimony
以上供悦
was provided by Sr Inspector Ming
是由内务部刘建明高级督察提供
The independent investigation
现独立调查小和组两位各警司
committee
及助理警务上处长
unanimously believed the testimony
一致信任刘高级督察所有供司
Ming's killings of Bily and Yan
站裁定划建明高级督察
have been ruled legal
击兹CIB林国平警遇实属合法
lt has been confirmed that
也证实林国平
Bily was a mole sent by Sam
是圩琛操控潘入警队的内好
Its over at last
终於水落石出了
You guys believe me?
你们相信我唉 ?
Anyway its all over
都已经过去了
Wait
你稍等
Got it Your parking space
知道你的停车位
Wait 3 more weeks. Yes
三个星期左右差不多， 是
Bye
再见
Sergeant Chan
陈警官
Your uniform is ready
你的制服已经洗好了
Drop by when youre free
如果你有空就过来取
fnot, 1 can send it to you
不然的话，我给你途过去
Sure, no problem
可以，没天傈
Good. DK
好
Too bad Billy destroyed the CCTV
电梯内的监视器给林国平弄坏了
orit wouldnt have dragged so long
事情才拖了二庆久
Our bosses harp on accountability.
现在上椒什么都要半责
Lucky that we Work together, So no red tapes
渤好，大家自己人，手续快多了
You can come back to IA next month
你下个月就可调回内其部
Exhausted?
累不累 ?
Take a vacation with Mary
累就请假，和Mary去散散心
Hello
好
Isign the documents tomorrow
我会到律师所签名
Sure
行，行
Yes
好
Everything can be separated
可以分
Everything except the baby
什么都可以分，孩子不能分
Sergeant Chan, your uniform's ready
陈和警官，你的制服洗好了
上youre not free, 1 can send it
你有空哮 ? 汉空我找人途过去
1 can do that too
我也行
OK, wait for me. Bye
好 ' 你等我， 再见
Have 1 done something wrong?
过位警官，有何得罪?
1 feel like beating people up today
我今天特别想打人
Why make such a scene, SP Yeung?
警官，运床有疝情 ?
These Taiwanese are arms dealers
过两个台湾老大是走私军火的
My appointment didnt show up
狗了客人，客人汽来
They're bored so keptthem company
我见他傅扰了获，就来陪陪他们
Nothing wrong, huh?
对不对 ?
Sure
对
1work in the Security Wing
我是警察保安科的
1 hate guys coming here all spiffed out
我最讨厌衣著光鲜的人在过儿玩
You got so many men, Lend me a hand
你过床多兄弟在，攻攻忙
Don't give me a hard time
That should make it easier
过檬吧
You wanna set me Up?
干嘛,你想冤枉人?
ls it better now?
是不是好点 ?
Weve already written the report
报告我们早就寅好
Half a kilo. Minimum 8 to 10 years
过壬半公斤， 起友要坐十年八载
Ask two kids to come back with me
等会儿叫两个小弟跟我回去
That's what they're gonna say
冰取口供的时候就褒
They saw them take out some drugs
看见两个台湾人突然说了一包毒品出来
As good guys do, they beat them up
便见义筋为 ，接了他一顿
II give them
我会向警民关傈科申请
Good Citizen Awards
[好市民桨」输他们
How about that?
好不好 ?
Sounds good
好
Take them in
把他们带走
Be gentle
客气些
Sir Sir you cant go in
先生你不能进去
Yeung, dont go too far
杨锦柴，你别起尺欠绝
All these years, you and me
过床多年来， 我玫了你不少忙
You want me dead?
你过是想我死
上f1 fall, you'll go down with me
我有事，你也休想有好日子过
Give me a chance, would you?
兄弟一场， 你过一个机会也不给我 ?
"One Month Later”
[一个月后J
Delivery from OCTB?
重案租也途外豆 ?
1 was transferred to IA yesterday
从昨天起，我和重案租的咖味
together with the coffee
铀来内季部陪你
Sit down
坐
lve stopped drinking
戒了
lneed pills to sleep lately
过阵子，吃安虐华才能睡
上1take coffee, 1 can't sleep
喝了咖啡会睡不著
Life is so unpredictable
世事有时真允料
1used to hate IAthe most
我以前最讨屎内范部
And now 1 have to work here
汉想到现在和铀了过来
You dont seem to like it here
不满意 ?
1 can transfer you elsewhere
不如把你铜走好了
Are you kidqding?
哪壬
1 moved here because of you
要不是你，我也不原意调过来
The flles are on your desk
档案都在桌上
The first file
第一份
[his sarge killed himself in front of his ex-boss, Yeunl
陈仅警长在也上司杨锦妆面前自杀
IA is working on several big cases
最近内其部调查攀件大案子
Security deals with politics
你知道保安科是搞政治的
Everything is classified there
一切都要保密
They wont answer any questions
不管你要什么资料，一律有问无答
We found an envelope on the sarge's desk
不过 我们在陈俊那里找到过封信
Theres atape inside
信壬有一盒带子
Its a chat between him and Sam
里面有陈俊与埋琛的谈话片段
ltturns out he was Sam's mole too
原来陈俊也是埋琛的人
Besides Chun
除了他之外
several officers also committed suicide or vanished
半年来有殉名警员自料或失足
They are proved to be Sam's moles
都证实是埋琛的人
After Sam's death
上面怀疑圭琛死后
SP Leung suspects one of the moles
wants to clear his ass of
有内奸想洗底
and kill everybody else
所以科人溅口
SP Leung ordered to dig out this guy ASAP
梁警司下兮要画快把过个人找出来
Its a close shave this morning
可知道今天多危隙 ?
A package was delivered to SP Leung
一大早有人泛了一袋带子给梁警司
Guess what's inside
知道是什和三 ?
Tapes of us supplying intel to Sam
是我们向埋琛报信的录香带
Lucky that the sarge is one of us
好在梁警司下面那个警长是自己人
How many more of us are there?
知不知道还有闪个人?
Including you, there are five
连你在内有五个
Ronald, this is Inspector Ming
Rona1d， 是刘督察
lve left something at Admin
治什么 ， 我漏了些东西在庶务部
lve dug up something about Chun
刘和警官，你叫我铀查陈俊，我查到了
He was in the Police Bowling Team
陈俊是警察保前球队成员
Wait
你稍等
Inspector Ming, thats what you need
刘和警官， 你要的东西在过儿
Good
好
Im off to Iunch now
我先去吃记
Thanks
Go on
He used to go to SCAA for practice
陈俊平时都在南华会练球
He rented his place from JJ Investment Co
租房给陈俊的那问金菊投资有限公司
This company owns 3 big units
名下有三个上干尺的物业
The owner is Shen, a Mainlander
公司由一个叫沈澄的内地人所持有
中email you the info later
三个物业的资料，稍后发短讯答你
No, send them to me now
不，你现在就发给我
Inspector Ming
刘和警官
fm Yeung from Security Wing
我是保安科的杨锦业
1 applied for a parking space
我申请的那个车位
Let me check
我替你查一下
1 waited a whole month
我等了整整一个月
1 dont wanna push you
我不是催你，不过
But how much longer will it take?
想知道还要等多久
Sorry, but lve moved back to IA
不好意思 ， 我已经铀往内务部了
1 know
我知道
But Admin asked me to contact you
但庶务部的同事叫我来找你
lts approved last month
你的申请一个月前已批准了
Your parking space is at B3A6
车位是B3A6
We couldn't reach you
找了你一个星期也找不到
lve taken a month off
我放了一个月假
IA was investigating me, You should know
你们内其部正在钴查我， 你知道的
1 do
我知道
Well, investigating Admin today?
人怎应，现在来调查席务部 ?
No. Just picking up a uniform
来拿回制服
lts a sarge's uniform, Inspector
过是警长制服， 督察 ?
belonged to the sarge who killed himself in front of yY
就是死在你面前那个管长的制服
Itake it back for investigation
拿回去调查
Wasn't the case closed already?
案子不是已经结束了唉 ?
True, or your break isn't over yet
对，不然你还汽放完假呢
Thanks
Youre welcome
不客气
B3A6
Have we met before?
我们以前网过吗 ?
1 dunno
汽有
D'you know Shen?
可了过一个叫沈澄的人 ?
Mind your own business
汉脾过 ，不关你的事，管好自己的事吧
Inside Chun's locker
在陈俊保前球场的储物杠壬
we found these photos
找到沽些相片
This guy is Shen
相片里面那个人叫沈澄
He used to be Sam's business partner
他以前是埋琛的生意拍描
This other guy is SP Yeung
另外那个，就是我们保安科主管杨锦党
1think he is responsible for sarge's death
我雇洛他与陈俊的死有很大关傈
SP Leung could be Sam's man we're searching for
杨锦业可能就是内好
OK
限
OK. See you in an hour
好 ' 一宣见
Youre so nice
你真好
You see him as soon as you're back
一回来就来看他
Youre anice guy too
你也很好
Thanks to you
要不是你
he could die as a cop
他死了也当不回警察
Thats my duty，
份内事
1 dont know why I helped him
我也不知道涡什和三会攻他
lonly knew him for 5 months or So
认识他五个多月
lve seen him 21 times in total
见过他二十一次
He's a good cop
他是个好警察
Everyone wouldve helped him
任何人都会属他
Where're you going? 川take you
去哪 ? 我途你
lm back
我回来了
Let's start
那咱们开始吧
Therere no triads in China
中国是汽有黑社会的， 知道唉 ?
What China needs is wealth
国家需要财富啊
Triads are all life-and-death
黑社会谈的是生死，生意谈的是生财
Today, we're here to talk business
今天我们是跟二大哥来谈生意的
But rm a real triad
我可真的是黑社会
No
不
To me, you're the best businessman
埋大哥在我心目中是最好的生意人
My brother said so too
我大哥也过床襄
We have a hundred mill to spend
我们现在有一估次金不知往哪放
We wanna invest in your business
想放到埋大哥你运盘生意
Well ask no questions
生意上的事我们绝不过周
Its one country, two systems
一国两制嘛
As long as money breeds money
只要是能生财生财
welllet you run the show
主权的事就随便随便啦
You still believe in that?
你还相信和过个吗 ?
We believe in our Mainland ties
我信我们在内地的关傈是你无法拒移的
Youthink a Hong Kong triad
你相信和当个香港黑社会
can outlive a Mainland businessman?
合比做中国生意人长命吗 ?
Without my brothers connection
汽我大哥的关保
your business in China won't last
你现在内地的生意， 我看也做不成
Sam, youre a Buddhist, right?
埋先生，你真的信佛 ?
Glory to Amitabha
阿疆陀佛
ls the feng shui good here?
过壬的风水真的运床好 ?
The best in Hong Kong
好 ， 全香港最好
1 want a longevity tablet here
我想在过儿圈块长生位
For which member of your family?
和给府上哪们 ?
For my wife
我太太
She died half a year ago
我太太半年前过身了
And also for myself
还有我
Such a small gig, I handle it
小事，包在我身上
Asmall gig?
小事 ?
Asmall gig
让事
小事
哮记s so small let my men do it
小事嘛,就沾小弟们去做
We'll see how they'l handle it
看看他们能做成什么样子
Goodbye
不泛了
Bye
慢走
Keung
傻强
You'll deal with his men
你去跟他的小弟谈谈生意
Are you kidding, Boss?
真的，琴哥?
Im an idiot. 1 will mess it up
我是傻子，你不怕我给搞磺了 ?
What does this smile mean?
笑甚订，到底什么意思 ?
Excuse me
不好意思
So loaded?
过床多 ?
Jealous or what?
眼红啊 ?
ls itlegit? Be careful
网不见得光 ? 小心点
Dont worry, Boss
你别要我了，老半
You should know how much cash 1 have
我有多少鳞,你会不知道 ?
Want aloan?
想借加花就说好了“， 不用恐畸
Whats this?
过是什么 ?
Your daughters pocket money
你女儿满月的
Youre a dad. Spend more time home
当爸爸了“， 多点回家 ， 别太拼命
You sure look thinner lately
最近瘦了和运床多 ?
None of your business. Thanks
别管我。谢谢
Whore these two guys?
那两个是什么人 ?
Only know theyre Mainlanders
只知道是内地人
Anything else?
还有了呢 ?
Shen was born in Taiyuan, Shanxi
沈澄是山西太原人
An entrepreneur who was drafted
民淮企业家，当深兵
Dealt in antiques and transport
在内地搞古董圈帝和运输
Started from scratch, he's loaded
白手显家，现金充足
He came to Hong Kong a year ago
一年前来香港发展
His bro Liang joined him recently
他鞠弟沈亮最近才跟他
and involved in shady businesses
负责见不得光的事
Sam's been eyeing the Chinese market
替琛运赤年想在内地发展
He wants you to talk about what?
他叫你去跟他谈什生 ?
Co-operation
谈合作吧
Liang
宽哥
Yan
老陈
Sit down，
坐
By yourself?
一个人 ?
You too, Liang?
亮哥，, 你也是一个人嘛
We have lots of nightclubs in China
我们在内地有夫十家夜店
All protected by local big shots
全都是各省有力人士关照的
Big shots
有力人士
Your goods can ride on our network easily
到时候你们的角就可以赐通扰阻
We have businesses in eleven cities
我们谈的可是十一个城市的生意呀
Im sorry
不好意思
Well, how's the talk so far?
怎样，跟他谈的怎样 ?
Not bad
不错
See an ashtray in front of you?
桌上是否有个类灰缸 ?
Pick it up and smash it in his head
拿起来，硬他的头
Smash him
征呀
磺他的头
Im screwed
糟了
What happened?
怎厅了 ?
Mary is pregnant
Mary有嘉了
Congratulations, Boss
恭喜， 长官
But we're not married yet
蕉什么喜，和还没结婚呢
Get married then
那就结婚吧
Huh, is it necessary?
有二个需要唉 ?
Or she can have an abortion
不要就打掉
Were already engaged
已经广册了
Got it
知道
We can go now
可以走了
OK, Ilets go
好 ，走
Long time no see
很久汽见
But 1 saw you last week in China with a broad
上星期在观澜看见你和一个刀
You dont have to shout
别过应大声
Security people are full of secrets
保安科特别多秘密
Time for a break
停一下
Hey, what's going on?
喂，干什和码 ?
What are you guys doing here?
你们在干什么 ?
Sorry, SP Wong
黄警官，不好意思
We're asked to take some mug shots
上头叫我们来拍兢张照
ldont know whats going on either
我也不清楚什么回事
1 asked CIB to open a file
是我叫CI8开个档案
and take a picture of everyone, anything wrong?
给过位拍张遗照， 不行吧 ?
Officers, are you done?
各位警官，金了吧?
Wow, everybody's here
过磋热关 ?
We were on the trail of Mr. Shen
本来我在剧查沈先生
But that led us to Sam by chance
但汽想到却跟上了埋先生
We even busted Sam's man
还抓了赫先生的人回来
IIet CIB handle the triads
我对黑社会不熟， 所以交给重案租
Sam, long time no see
琛哥， 好久汉见,好唉 ?
What brings you here?
何事牵你来过儿了 ?
Just accompanying some friends
陪朋友而已
You HK Police is so inefficient
你们香港警察办事效率真低
Ispeed it up then
那我就快点
He beat you up. Wanna press charges?
他把你打成运样，要不要投诉 ?
上f not, then sign here
不投诉就得个字
1beat you Up. Wanna press charges?
我把你打成过样，要不要投诉 ?
Youre out of your mind
和警官，你别要了
Stand there
站好
36G
Ke介强 le走 go
Wait
等等
Do you recognize me?
你启不座得我 ?
But 1 recognize you, Be careful
我记得你，你小心点
SP Wong
黄警官
They're all yours
怎样处置他们，你决定
No need. We know each other So well
不用了“， 大家过应熟
The CIB colleagues, you can go now
CIB的同事先走，谢谢
Thanks, Ming
小副 ,谢谢
Is my duty
公事公闪而已， 走
Let's go
收队
Whats your game?
你想摘事唉 ?
You think its a game?
你攻得我在搞事 ?
Its life-and-death
会出人命的
Im glad you know that
知道就好
Hurry up and thank me
快谢谢我
For what?
谢什三?
Look what youre doing now
你看你在做什么 ?
Just eating
在吃东西
Youre eating shark fin
你吃的是角翅
角示呀 , 你想想
Boss took me to Thailand last time
琛哥上次带我去泰国
1 had shark fin and then 1 moved up
请我吃完鱼翅，我就上了位
You have shark fin. You'll move Up
现在你吃鱼翅 ， 你上位了
Boss is mean but he buys you shark fin
琛哥一毛不拔， 也请你吃角翅
Just think about 江
你自己还不想想 ?
Take him
拿下
Let go of him
放开手，别筷来
Boss
琛哥
You let them take Yan to China?
你任他被带走 ?
Ask him why he smashed his head
你辣他干嘛古人家的郑
He smashed his head?
砸人家的头 ?
Its no big deal. On the street
过有什么 ? 出来混的
either you smash me or 1 smash you
不是你磺人“，就是被人硬
Yan has smashed his head, right?
磺破头吗 ?
How about this?
运柑行了唉 ?
ls that OK now?
行不行?行了嘲 ?
Liang
沈亮
Are you here to make a scene?
你他是是跑著搞事
Or are you here for business?
还是做生意啊 ?
Scram
濠
We are even now
扯平了
Let's talk business
谈生意吧
1 heard your arms business is huge
你的军火生意做得挺大的
上fyou can let me chip in
要是能狗让我插一手
then the blood they have spilled
我觉得他们两个流的血
will not be in vain
挺值得
Boss
琛哥
So what about it?
怎床样 ?
Youhave agrudge against me?
不漠意我 ?
No
汽有
Ever met a guy who seems nice
你有遇过一种人“， 不知道何时对你好
but might whack you any moment?
更不知道何时会视你 ?
lve met someone like that before
So what's your conclusion, Boss?
琛哥，汪次你怎样看?
Im wondering
我也奇怪
Why he didnt whack you
人也竹什么不杀你 ?
You look afterthem from now on
以后内地过人条财路就交给你
Take this
先花著
Shen's not what he seems
沈澄的青景不简单
Security is on his trail
保安科最近在调查他
Could be related to arms smuggling
应该跟偷运军火有关
Sam stopped all his deals in China
赫琛最近停止所有内地交易
Theyre gonna work together soon
人也们该会一起搭档
Thats big shit
过可是大买误
What should 1 do?
Youre not at the shrink yet?
你还不去看心理医生 ?
Why should 1 see a shrink?
好好的看什么心理医生 ?
You beat peocple up
你打偏人
1 persuaded Department of Justice
我好不容易才广律政司不告你
to send youto a shrink instead of jail
不用坐牢，判你接受心理治疗
lts fine you don't wanna go
不喜坎就拉倒
See you in jail
看律政司怎样判吧， 再见
Hello
喂，喂
What's the address?
地址在哪呀 ?
l have an appointment with Dr. Lee
麻烦你，我钩了李医生
Overthere, please
过兆请
Planning to spend the night here?
今隐在过儿过夜 ?
1 cant fall asleep in my clinic
我在办公室睡不著的
Unlike him
他不同
He said since he's an undercover
他说，做区底以来
he could only fall asleep here
只有在我过儿才睡得著
1 still remember
我还记得
He told me that night
那天了晚上
Everythingll be OK after tomorrow，
他说过了明天便汽事
And then he died
谁知就过样死了
Youre a doctor
你是医生来的
You still keep his fle?
通留著他的病历 ?
He's dead, but he's stil a patient
他死了， 但还是我的病人
Let's go
走吧
OK
好
"Three Hours Later
[三小时和合J
We found an envelope on sarge's desk
我们在陈俊的位子找到过封信
Theres atape inside
壬面有盒带子
Its a chat between him and Sam
人录了他跟韩琛的谈话片段
After Sam's death
上头怀疑圭琛死后
SP Leung suspects one of the moles
wants to clear his ass of
有内鬼想洗底
and kill everybody else
所以科人溅口
1think he is responsible for sarge's death
我雇澳他跟陈俊的死有很大关傈
SP Yeung could be Sam's man we're searching for
杨锦业可能就是内果
Do you understand what 1 said?
我的话你到底明不明白 ?
Sorry
对不起，不好意思
1 wont sign ifshe doesnt show Up
纺之她不见我，我是不会签的
Got it?
你清楚唉 ?
OK
就过样
My wife is divorcing me
我和老婆关翻，可能要享婚
Did 1 scare you? [m sorry
哇到你了 ? 不好意思
Be careful
那你小心点
Of what?
我小心什和三 ?
Your cars next to mine. 1 drive badly
你的车停在我旁渤， 我技术很差
上1Sscratch your car look for me
如果弄花了，找我
Im a good driver. Don't worry
我技术很好 ' 你可以放心
The Taiwanese will be discharged next week
上个月抓的两个台湾人，下星期出院
Taiwan authorities have no comments
台湾当局一点表示都洛有
Mainland's police will come for repatriation
内地会派公安来， 办引渡手续
Their boss is a good friend of mine
那个公安长官跟我很熟
So stick to the plan
大家按奸划行事，小心一点
When those big shots arrive
那些大人来到
banquets and shopping are inevitable
融不了去吃海鲜， 圈名牌
Make sure they feel welcomed
好好招呼也们
How about the nightclub?
带他们去 「中国城」 比较好吧
1think Macau is better
那不如去澳门
Youre not afraid of paparazzi9?
太张揭了，碰上记者怎闪 ?
IJjust bag them
照蕾，麻包袋重头
OK, you bring the bags
那你负责带麻包袋
SP Yeung
杨警官
Its Chun's memorial next week
下星期，是陈俊侍辰
We wanna hire some monks for a Service
大家想涛点钱做场法事
Make sure its decent
办得体面些
Yes
轧
正
Back to the Taiwanese police
褒回公安那件事
Talk to the Macau guys tomorrow
明天去澳门跟老大们褒
Let them plan the evening
晚上的一切活动由也们安排
Italk to them about security
保安方面， 我亲自去谈
Without planning, it be a mess
一点计划都洛有， 会出人现子
Then we wont have a good time
我们可要吃不了兜著走
Any addition to your testimony?
李氏生， 还有补充吗 ?
No
汽了
Call us if you got extra information
有需要的话，打电话给我
Thanks
All set?
好了嘲 ?
Yes
好了
Can ltouch this?
东西我可以袖了 ?
Yes
可以
OK, thanks
好，谢谢
ls everything OK?
人怎样，治事吧 ?
lts like that when lcame in
回来的时候，就种样
They stole some cash and watches
丢了些钱，不见了顽焦贸
And the computer is gone
还有电脑
Might as well start ffom scratch
也好，一了百了， 重新再来
Butthe computers useless to them
他从我的电脑也汉用
1 Iocked it with my password
我用密码向住的
They wont know its my license plate number
不会党床巧猜到密码就是车牌号吧
Your eyes are red. You didn't sleep?
眼睛过麻和红，没睡 ?
Been working on several cases
在查兴件案子，泡天了
You should get some sleep
休息一下吧
Everything'll be OK after tomorrow
好， 过了明天就汉事
1 have to go, Call me
我先走 ， 有事打电话给我
Mr. Chan
陈先生
"2002.8.16. The First Session"
「2002.8.16，第一次介面。J
Mr. Chan, Im Dr. Lee
陈先生，我是李心儿轿生
1 am obligated to tell you
我有义务告诉你
Youre ordered to undergo treatment
现在接受的心理治疗是由律政署转介
In the coming 6 months
未来六个月
you should complete the treatment
你要如期完成疗程
Ithen submit a report to the Court
完成之后，我会寅份报告给法庭
The Court will base on this report
法庭会根据过心理评估
and decide if you should go to jail
决定你用不用接受监禁
Jail?
监禁 ，
lsntthe treatment all there is?
不是治疗完就没事吧 ?
You should follow the doctors orders
在疗程期间， 你必须罚守医生的指示
Orthe Court can revoke the sentence
否则律政署有权推翻之前对你的判决
And detain you for handling
直接途进拘留所等候发落
Got it
知道
Excuse me
不好意思
Damn you SP Wong
黄志诚，你过个王八蛋
You dont need te call the cops
李医生， 你不用报警
Just give me a call
你打给我不就行了
You have my number right?
你有我的号码嘛
orlllbecome awanted criminal
你运样做，我会被通第的
"The Second Session"
[第二砍会面
Mr. Chan, Im Dr. Lee
陈先生，我是李心儿轿生
1 am obligated to tell you
我有义务告诉你
Youre ordered to undergo treatment
你现在接受的心理治疗是由律政署转介
In the coming 6 months
未来六个月壬
you should complete the treatment
你要如期完成疗程
Youllthen submit a report to the Court
然后你会把过份心理报告交给法庭
The Court will base on this report
看法庭处理怎样
And might put me in jail. 1 got ii
不满意就监禁我，我明白
Please sign here then
请你把同意书签了
We think you have a violent streak
由於我们怀疑你有严重暴力惨向
We'l use hypnotism for treatment
所以我们的疗程会以催眠为主
Hypnotism?
众眠 ?
You signed the papers
你短了同意书
Hypnotism?
是催眠唉 ?
You can refuse
你有权不接受
But the Court can revoke
但律政卡也有权推翻之前对你的
And lock me Up, right?
监禁我，对吧
Go ahead
随便吧
Hypnotize me then
众吧
Let's begin
那我们开始
Please introduce yoursef
你可否介绍一下自己
Talk about your family
或者谈谈你的家庭
Mr. Chan?
陈先生?
Mr. Chan
陈先生
Can you co-operate?
你合作点行唉 ?
1 was practicing
我练色一下
In case you cant hypnoetize me
万一你催眠不了我
lcan hypnotize myself for you
我也可以自我催眠来配合你
You know
我各个人呢
Awillis particularly strong, Its not easy to hypnotize
特别坚强， 不是你想众就能催的
1 haven't started yet
我还没开始
Not yet
还汽
You wanna know my story?
我家庭唉 ?
My surname wasn't really Chan
其实我不姓陈
1 was an ilegitimate child
我是个私生子
My dad was a drug pusher
我老爸是毒晨
1had to work since 上 was little
我从小就出来混闵家
learned two hundred grand a month
当时“， 一个月上嫌二十兢万
lbrought a Porsche at seventeen
十七诚就祥了名焉跑车
1hired two drivers coz
后来想起自己没有胡照
1didn't have a drivers license
便请了两个司机
This shrink thing is useless
看心理医生，自讨苦吃
Shrink or jail time. You choose
心理医生、坐牢， 自己挑
She wants to hypnotize me
她要催眠我呀
flspilthe beans
万一下她魏眠了，漏了什么
don't blame me
我不负责
Its not that easy to be hypnotized
汽那床容易吧
Don't concentrate and she can't
你精神不集中，不会给催眠
Its tough not to concentrate
汽那床容易不集中 ?
Dr. Lee is nice
那个李医生好
Nice person
好人
You won't understand
你不舍懂的
"The Third Session"
[第三砍会面
Yoeu are looking at the sky with lots of cloud
你现在望著天空， 天上有很多才
You are enveloped by warm water
你在水里，暖水包国著全身
You feel weightless
你几得自己失去重量
Youre floating on water
全身浮在水上
You slowly open your eyes
慢慢卓开眼睛
The sky is so close
天 ， 跟你很近接著
Whatre you doing?
你想怎样 ?
fm hungry
我斌了
Gotta eat something
斌了不吃东西很念胃的
Are you done?
吃完了唉 ?
Yes, kind of
算吃完了
Lets start again
再来
Can you See the Sea?
你看见那大海吗 ?
The water is so warm
你在水里 ， 海水很温暖
lt envelops your whole body
包国著全身
You feel
你攻得自己
What now?
你的花样挺多呀
Nothing really
也不是花样
1 might oversleep during hypnosis
我怕被你催眠，睡过头就不好了
Better set my alarm
所以先铀好阀逢
lts not difficult to remember
那床钦记嘲 ?
"The Fourth Session"
[第四次会面
One Mercedes to Zhanjiang
一辆奔岗去湛江
One Land Cruiser to Zhuhai
一辆越野车去珠海
Write it down if you can't remember
不记得 ? 找张狐写啊
The cabin cruisers need new motors
快艇当然要新马过，二手质抛锚怎闪 ?
Pink?
粉红色 ?
We are smuggling, not sailing
现在走私，你以加滑水呀 ?
My fax number
我的传真号码 :
21918125
No fax machine?
泊有传真机 ?
Why ask my fax number then?
那还问我传真号码 ?
E-mail?
电邮 ?
E-mail address?
电邮地址 ?
No e-malil
泊有电邓
Sorry, but lve been really busy
针不起，最近工作比较忙
So are you done With your business?
社园的事你忙完了没有 ?
Let's talk about your family
忙完了就说府你家庭
You said your dad had 3 Wives
上回你褒你爸爸有三个老婆
You have 16 sisters
你有十六个姐姐
Lets talk about your twelfth sis
就谈谈你跟十二姐的天保
Heh, havent
我还泡
Are you OK?
汽事吧 ?
Get away
走开
Why so impulsive? 1 havent listened
干嘛运床币动 ， 我还没匠
Better now?
好点吗 ?
The repoert for the Court
律政署的报告怎样写
doesn't matter to me
对我来说站不重要
Im a doctor. 1 only wanna cure you，
我是医生，我只想把你治好
You can leave anytime fyou like
不原意的话，你随时可以走
But Ive been trying to tell you
但有件事我想告诉你很久了
上 you keep lying, 1 can't help you
"The … Session'"
[第......次会面J
Dr. Lee
李攻生
What did 1 do besides sleeping?
我刚才除了睡，还做过什么 ?
You dont remember what you did?
你做过什么自己不知道吗 ?
1 do but fm not sure
我知道，但不大肯定
Forget it, Bye
算了,再见
Dr. Lee
李攻生
lfind you particularly nice to me
我总是恤得你对我特别好
Youve got a crush
其写你对我是不是
Delusion
妄想症
Delusion?
是妄想症唉 ?
No wonder
座怪
Bye
再见
Whats with you? Looking so smug
网吊啦， 吉庆好笑?
The doc said youre dying tomorrow?
医生说你明天就死 ?
You won't understand
你不会明白
You think 1 have delusion?
你攻得我有妄想症吗 ?
Delusion?
妄想症 ?
Yes, you do
你有啊
Maybe hypnotism makes me delusional
可能催眠太多，催出个妄想症来
That cant be helped
真没办法
Hey, watch out
就是那个你小心开车呀
So many cars
过磋多车?
Im a normal guy
就是找一个女人
But she makes me all confused
把你搞得量头量有瞄
So Ispill my guts
然后广你吐真言的那种
lt has to do with Sigmund Freud
不关女人事，是佛洛依德
According to psychoanalysis
心理学上是过床褒的
hypnosis gets to your subconsciousness
催眠可和浊入人类的洒意识
Once it reaches your subconsciousness
进入你的洒意识
it can reach your darker side
就可找到你的险暗面
Then it can heal your traumas
找到隐暗面，有助治疗心理创伤
And then with symbolic memories
到时还有图像记居呢
Its so deep. Are you showing off?
说得如此深奥，距谁呀 ?
1 cant help 并
我不想啊
Its written in Shen's Readers Digest
是沈大哥泛我的书是过样襄的
Are you buddy buddy with Shen now?
你跟沈瀑和好了 ?
Not at all
好个屁
He tries to buddy buddy me instead
是他自己靠过来的
Mr. Shen
沈大哥
Let me apologize for Yan
以前的事，是阿仁不对
Iapologize for him
我代他跟你褒对不起
Pal, ever heard the saying
小第，有没有凡褒过
Men are changed by events，
not events by men?
事情改释人，人改释不了事情 ?
Without the past, there's no present
不打不成交， 没有过去， 哪有现在 ?
Im sorry
得罪了
What?
你设甚磋 ?
Great speech
你褒得很好
Where's Sam?
畦大哥呢 ?
He sent the two of us
琛哥说我们两个搞定
Sam
琛哥
Reading?
在看书 ?
Any recommendations?
有什么好介绍 ?
How about you?
你呢 ?
How To Become Rich In One Day
[如何一日致富」 ，缕好
lm not short of cash
镑 ' 我不缺
l helped you alot over the years
运些年我玫你不少
You speak first, Chief Inspector
话是否该你先说，绩督察 ?
You know everything 1 know already
我知道的，你也知道
Cut the spiel. Will you help me?
不说订话，你攻不必我 ?
Yoeu help me. 1help you
你划我， 我虱你
We help each other
互相攻忙
Good
好
What are you doing here?
你在过儿干什么 ?
1 am here to
我在运儿
He is gone
走了
Whosthat guy?
他是谁 ?
Apimp
皮人条客
Why are you following him?
你跟著他堤磋 ?
Actually Im a pimp too
其实我也是皮休客
1wanna know if he's dating my gals
我看他有汽有泡我的刀
Actually, !m short of cash
其实，我最近手头很紧
How about hiring me?
不嫌奢的话，不妨考虑一下我
Be serious, doc
别要我啦，李医生
Be serious, pimp
别要我啦 ， 皮人条客
Hello, Internal Affairs
内务部
Boss, 1 saw Yeung with Sam today
老闭，今天我看见埋琛和杨锦业见面
He may be a mole. Run a check on him
杨锦业可能是内奸， 你查一下
Sam's deal with Shen may start soon
埋琛与内地人的交易，麻该在过淆天
Uncle Chan, why so late?
陈伯“，过订唤搞什么 ?
Refil the water dispenser
来换水啊
You're good
你好属害
You know when we run out of water
各里汽水你也知道
Dont just talk, Give me a hand
快来草一把，别说订话
Damon, help
Damon，玫帮忙
Why said nothing just then?
人怎友刚才不襄话 ?
Yan just sent me a tape
陈永仁宕了盒带子给我
Yan sent you a tape?
陈永仁寄带子给你 ?
Wait for me
你等我
Whats the matter with you?
你怎厌了，小划 ?
1got something important to do
我有点事
Wait
等等
What?
干什么 ?
Youve been back for two days
你来过壬两天了
You havent seen anybody but me
除我之外，其他人你膛汽见过
Am 1supposed to greet everyone?
是不是要我跟他们逐个打招呼 ?
Did 1 scare you?
哇到你 ?
Im sorry
不好意思
1 dunno why you
我不知道你把自己
locked yourself up for two days
锁在房间壬两天干嘛 ?
Don't take everything on yourself
大论什么事，别只自己承担好唉 ?
Everything'll be OK after tomorrow
过了明天就汉事
Ming
小刘
The door is over there
门口在那还
Lets give itto OCTB
交给重案租
Did you listen to it?
双过那盒带子没有 ?
No
汽有
iam and Shen'ss transaction will take place in two day
后天埋琛会跟沈澄交易
There'l be lets of arms and coke
有大批军火和可卡因
Icontact you before take-off
出发前我会通知你
So Sam doesnt trust you fully
看来圩琛还治完全信任你
Beware of Yeung first
你要小心杨锦辣
1 will
我会
Can you bust him?
可有证据抓住他 ?
You saw them together,. That's not enough
他和埋琛在一起， 和过证明不了什么
How can 1 bust him?
怎样抓 ?
Boss, [m risking my life for you
老轩， 我在外面出生入死
So dont run that bullshit on me
你却澡沛水 ?
川take care of Yeung
杨锦柴那漫，我会搞定
Its you?
你”
Don't worry. Ming's a great help
放心吧，小刘能攻上忙
Do you know what youre saying?
你设甚磋 ?
You wont die if its not for him
要不是他，你也不会出事
lt was an accident
那次是意外
Didnt you want us dead?
你不是想我们死吗 ?
1only wanna be a good guy
我想做好人“，我不知道会摘成过样
Can you give me another chance?
再给我一次机会
Sorry, but Im a cop
多不起，我是警察
Are you OK?
怎床样，你没事吧 ?
fm fine
我没事
Im OK
汽事
Do you know what you just did?
知不知道你刚才干什么 ?
1 know. What about it?
知道 ，干什么 ?
Can you take me back to the clinic?
途我回办公室吧
Sure. Are you DK?
好 : 你怎厅了?
OK. Let's go
来，走
Good morning, Dr. Lee
李医生, 早
Your hypnosis is great
你的众眠很管用
lm so relaxed
整个人都轻县了
1guess won't need to go to jail
按运样进度我想不用坐牢了吧 ，
Hypnotherapy is a two-Way process
催眠治疗，要你和我互相合作
上fyou don't tell the truth
你不说实话
1 can't help you
汽有人可以草你
Im already very co-operative
我很合作啊
You dont talk about the triads
如何加入黑社会，你不说
Thats OK. But even on matters
汽问题，但平时聊天
like your favorite food and fllms
喜坎看什么电影，喜坎吃什么
You still have to lie
你都要讼谎
Well that beats me
真不明白
Youre not me. You wont understand
你不是我，你不会明白的
The brain is not
上天给我们胶袋
made for keeping secrets
不是用作守秘密的
lremember when 1 was a kid
记得小时候
lstole a candy bar in a Supermarket
我在超级市场偷了一排巧克力
Its a foot long
家庭装，有一尺长
The manager caught me
我走到杠台时，和经理抓住我
1 was so scared 1 cried
我好害怕，不停的器
The manager finally let me go
结果那经理把我放了
Later 1 went there with my mom
后来我跟奸奸到同一家超级市场
And 1 saw the manager
网到同一个经理
1 felt he's staring at me
我觉得那经理好像老盯著我
1 was very Uneasy
很不自在
My mom asked me what was wrong
媚婚看见，癌我发生什么事
1 said the manager had molested me
我说那经理非礼过我
My mom called the cops
於是奸刀报警，警察来了
So the cops took the manager away
经理被带上和警车
He never told on me
那经理始终汉把我偷东西的事说出来
But Inever saw him again
最后我再也没见过他
Then 1 wentto college
直到我上了大学
Ifinally told this to a classmate
我终於跟一个同学说了真话
After 1 finished telling the story
说完之后
1 felt like a new-born
得自己好像重新做人一样
Can I really start over again?
我真的可以重新做人 ?
Do you trust me?
你相信我唉 ?
1 do
我相信
As long as you trust me
你相信我就行了
When did you join the triads?
你炎时并始加入黑社会 ?
1didnt wanna join the triads
我不想做黑社会
1 wanna be a good guy
我想做个好人“，汽想到
Butthen 1 met Mary
我遇上Mary
Your wife?
你太太 ?
She's Sam's woman
连琛的女人
Why do I have to talk about this?
我怎友会说运些 ?
You gotta trust me for hypnosis to work
我说过你要相信我，我才能催眠你
Then we can solve your problems，
才能解决问题
You cant solve my problems
你解决不了我的问题
My job is to betray folks around me
我的工作就是出喜身逮的人
1dunnc when 1 can stop
我不知道磷时才能停止
To survive
我要生存
] have to betray others
就要出豆身还的人
lm actually a cop
我是警察
lm a cop
1 dont wanna be Sam's mole
我不想做畦琛的人
Did 1 scare you?
把你咕壤了 ?
Im sorry
不好意思
Everything'll be OK after tomorrow
放心吧， 过了明天就汽事
Where were you? Today is D-Day
你去哪了 ?今天跟内地人交易呀
Today?
今天 ?
Yeah
是啊
1 forget
最近记性好差
Take out your phones
把电话都富出来
Distribute them
把它们分了
Yan
阿仁
You take the boat. There're arms
你跟阿祥的船，小心点，是军火
If anything goes wrong
万一有什么风吹草动
1 know
我知道
You drive me to the dockyard
你跟我的车，去码头
D-Day of Shen and Sam's deal
埋琛和沈澄的珠三角笋
will be tonight
今晚正式开始运作
They probably have heavy armories
那些歹徒可能有重型军火
We should wear bulletproof jackets
大家淮备防弹衣
The marine is standing by
水警已经候命
TeamAandB get ready at the slopes
第一、二队在外图兴个山头监视
Wait for my order
耻我命令
The operation is called off
今晚行动要取消
What are you saying?
你知不知道自己在说什么 ?
Thats an order from the top
过是上头的命令
An order from you or from the top?
是上椒的命令还是你的命令 ?
1 don't need to explain to you
我不用向你解释
lve been on Sam's trail for years
我追查埋琛好玖年
Explain your ties with Sam
你和他的关傈，也订该向我解释一下
Its Security's top secret
过是我们保安科的高度机密
ou can make formal inquiry to the Asst. Commission'
你可以写信或致电副警艺署长直接查询
CallIA
打电话到内范部半
Yes, Sir
是，长官
Sir
长官
Just do what Yeung said
杨警官说什么 ，你照著做
No way
不行
lts not as Simple as you think
黄，运件事不是你想的那厅简单
Its very simple for me
长官， 我知道，我的事就很简单
My man is risking his life out there
我有个兄弟在外面拼著命
Everybody in OCTB stays put
重案租今晚留下
Youre under disciplinary investigation
What kind of disciplinary issues?
我的部门有什么纪律问题，长官 ?
You dont follow orders. That's a disciplinary issue
你不服从命令，就是纪律有问题
Where are you going?
你去哪 ?
Back to my room, Sir
我回办公室等著，长官
Let's go
收队
Turn back
Ask everyone to follow our car
傻强，叫他们跟著我们的车
But Yan is in the transaction
琛哥， 阿仁正在交壬
Your wife agrees to meet you this afternoon
刘先生，你太太同意今天下午和你见面
ls that OK with you?
有没有问题 ?
Thank you
The people will come in today for repatriation
今天内地将派公安来办疑犯引渡手续
Make sure nothing goes wrong
大家别犯错，小心点
Damon and Fai, you stay here
Damon、阿晕，留在指挥部
Set the channel to 34879
大家将频率调到34879
Tell Transportation we can go now
通知交通部可以出发
Thank you
Ming, having fun in my office?
刘和警官，你在我办公室玩得开心唉 ?
Everyone, get ready and follow me
各单位淮人备，跟我来
Whats the matter Ming?
小刘 , 什么事 ?
Well bring Yeung in
请保安科椒头回来喝咖啡
Those police are chatting inside,
公安们在壬面聊著
Theyll be meeting our boss in fifteen minutes
十五分短和后跟我们团长开彰
Don't make any mistake
过次大家不要打睹睡
Damon and Fai, get the documents ready
Damon、阿晕，把资料准备好
Yeung
杨锦迷先生
Youre under suspicion for collusion with Sam
现怀疑你与埋琛集团有了关
Please come with us to IA
请你跟我们回内苏部协助调查
Ming, you know what youre doing?
刘和警官，你知不知道自己在干什么 ?
1 know
我知道
1 found a cassette tape
我找到盒带子
What tape? 1 don't get it
什么带子 ? 我不明白
Listen and you will
你了匠一蘑就会明白
Where's Mr. Sam?
畦先生在哪 ?
He's not here yet?
琛哥，还汽来吗 ?
Theyre empty
空的
Shen
大哥
Boss, the arms cost over ten mi
琛哥，那可是上干万的军火
Please give them back，
渤和给人家吧
Those Mainlanders are animals
你知道他们的来头，不好惹
What ifthey're here to set me up?
我哪知道他是否害我 ?
Which bitch told you that?
哪个漂蛋告诉你的?
My life told me so
What if youre wrong?
如果不是怎床柑 ?
Then 川 co-operate with them
不是就还和葵他，跟他合作
But Yan's gonna die either way
不管是或不是阿仁都要死，对吧 ?
Were all risking our lives here
出来混的，早就淮悍要没命了
1 almost died twice
我也曾死过两次
Boss, no more jokes
琛哥，别玩了琛哥
Boss
琛哥
1 have only one henchman
我只有一个手下
Dont do this to me
你忍心过样对我 ?
Tell me
设
Where are my goods?
我的货呢 ? 到哪去了 ?
Go ask Sam yourse[f
你自己周二琛吧
Why didnt you shoot my head?
告诉我，为什么不打我的头 ?
1didnt aim
我没瞄淮
Stand up
起来
You guys are together?
你们是一炙的?
You guys are together
你们是一伙的
Sorry, Im a cop
多不起，我是警察
Go ahead and shoot
随便开枪吧
Save me a bullet
让我省下一果子弹
What kinda cop are you?
你褒什么，汪还算是警察 ?
1got an "A" for writing reports
是的，我在警校是寅报告能手
After 1 kill you, 1 can write anything
亲了你们两个，我喜区怎样写都行
He's not Sam's man
他不是埋琛的人
Then you're not Shen
那你也不是沈澄
Youre in time
你来得正好
Come join us. Its entertaining
一起上邪，很有趣
So you don't wanna help me, Ming?
刘警官，你不想攻我?
1 do, but theyre watching me
不是，最近风赫比较紧
So youre not worried about me
原来你不是担心我
Youre worried about yourself
你担心的是你自己
Whatever You say
随便你怎友说
You'l deal with him
那你搞定他
Give me three days, 川run a check
给我三天，我查清楚再告诉你
Ming
刘和警官
Ming, this is your last chance
刘建明 ， 过是你最后机会
Ming, youre under arrest
刘建明 ， 我要拘捕你
Whatre you doing? Ming is over there
干什么 ? 刘建明在那膛 ， 你干什么 ?
We agreed to bust him, Why you help him?
我们说好要抓人也，你干嘛蔓他 ?
Yeung found this tape in your room
杨警官在你房间找到过带子
Why did you make such a big mess?
琛哥，干嘛益过糜大 ?
He is chasing after me. 1 have to kill him
过警察死咬著不放，他不死我就完蛋
Im taking charge now
现在运壬由我控制
IIook after your deal
如果你要出质，通知我
lve got it when we killed the cop today
一切搞定，今天久那警察的时候
Italk to you later
货已经收到,不跟你说了
Cuff him
备起他
Whatre you doing?
你干什么 ?
Get away, Sit down
走开，坐下
Sit down, Get away
坐下 ' 走开
Get away
走开呀
Get away, Whatre you doing?
走开，你干什么 ?
1told you to be careful
我说过 ， 叫你小心点
Why should 1 be careful?
我况什么要小心 ?
Im a good guy. Why should I be careful?
我是好人，竹什么要小心 ?
Why?
为什么 ?
1 worked so hard
我辛泣苦苦
Helping you guys
我替你们久光
killing all of Sam's moles
欠光埋琛的共底
Why cant you give me a chance?
各什么你不给我机会
各什么不给我机会 ?
1 wanna be a good guy too
我只不过想做个好人
Why dont you give me a chance?
你竹什么不给我机会 ?
Why? Answer me
力什么 ? 说呀
Sorry, Im a cop
多不起，我是警察
Im a cop too
我也是警察
Sure you won't go to the hospital?
你们傅真的不打算去医院 ?
People like me can't see the light
干我们各行见不得光
Same here
说的也是
More blood, more credits
多流点血， 回去才加分
Willthat cause you trouble?
汽给你添麻烦吧
Its just a report
只是一份报告
You trade intel with Sam. Be careful
你常跟埋琛交换情报，小心点
You should be careful. Sam set you Up
你也是，埋琛出误你
You wont bump into me every time
你不侍每次都傍伴地税到我
Wil we see each other again?
我们三个淆时才有机会再见面 ?
pass
不要了
Speak Mandarin
讲国语，讲国语
IIgo to Beijing next week. Join me
我下礼拜去北京，一块来吧
IIquit after this.
干完和吉事，我不干了
And you?
那你呢 ?
lm a snitch
我 ? 我是共底
We dont have holidays
哪有假期，长官 ?
OK
好了
See YOU
再见， 再见
You haven't told us
你还泡告六我们
Whats your name?
你叫什三名字 ?
Name?
名字
1 dunno
我也不知道
Just call me "Shadow."
就叫我影子吧
How corny
汽过床土吧 ?
About time for me, too
时间差不多了
Yoeu havent answered me
上次还治回答我
1asked ifyou remembered me
我问你记不记得我
Atthe cadet school in 1991
九一年在警校的时候
上you hadnt Ileft, 1 couldnt get the award
如果你漫走，我也拿不到优秀次
Ming is in critical condition at the hospital
刘建明已给途到医院去
The bullet penetrated his upper jaw
他现在情沈危列 ， 子弹打穿了上上显
and has entered his brain
留在肌子壬面
The doctor says even if he can survive
医生说即使可以保命
his brain will be seriously damaged
胶袋也可能严重受损
Stuff about him and the moles are all over the walls
in his room
刘建明房间壬头贴满他跟内鬼的将料
The whole IA has been covered with CCTV
整个肉部都装了闭路电视
all connected to SP Yeung's computer
都接到保安科杨警官的电脑壬
Mary
He wont make it
我想他来不了
Ten Days after Yan's Death
12002年12月”陈永仁殉职和后10日J
He's dead. Whats the point?
人他媳都死了，二还有什么用 ?
There're things weve gotta do
有些事还是要去做的
Hey pal, youre right
兄弟，你是对的
Everything'll be OK after tomorrow
李医生，过了今天就没事了
Iarrest Ming mysef
我一定会亲手逮捕刘建明
One Month Later
[一个月后J
Take it back
还给你
He made me a limper
他店我鬼成痪子
ls he Yan's friend too?
他也是阿仁的朋友 ?
They were in cadet school together
人也傅在警校是同学
Twelve Years Before
「十二年前
Now that you're in the cadet school，
you should follow the rules
进了警校， 就要守警校的规矩
Those who break the rules will be like him
不守规矩的人，就会像他一样
They will be expelled
开除
Who wants to trade place with him?
有谁想跟他交换 ?
Yeung, congrats for the Award
杨锦业，蕉喜你得到今年的奖章
If he weren't kicked out, it should have been his?
他如果泡被开除 ， 是否该了他来语 ?
Perhaps thats fate
可能过就是命还
Destiny is destiny
是粮份，就是概份
Men are changed by events, not events by men
往往是事情改灵人，人改释不了事情
But these two men
但是他们
They have changed certain events
冯改匆了一些事
Let bygones be bygones
好了“， 过去的都过去了
Tomorrow is another day
明天膛要开始
Seven Months Later
[七个月后J
Youre here?
你来了
The baby can say "papay"
青子介叫爸爸了
November 2002, Seven days before Yan's death
「2002年11月，陈永仁殉职前七日。j
He shot me so 1 Shot him back
人家拔枪打我，我不还击 ?
1 was just a punk at that time
当时“， 我的角色是黑社会
Stop bitching and learn from Yeung
你就只会怖我，拜旗你学学杨警官吧
Learn what?
学什么 ?
How to write a report
学人家怎样写报告
Did you kill anyone? Its big shit
你有汽有打死人 ? 打死人可不是小事
So its small shit 半1got killed?
打死我就是小事吧 ?
Send me a report
你交份报告给我
Isend you shit
我交个屁和给你
What did you say?
你褒甚床喇你
Scram
走
What do you mean?
走什么呀 ， 仁哥?
Time for lunch
午饭了
lve hardly finished breakfast
可我大吃过早餐呀
Do you wanna eat shit instead?
早餐吃过就得午餐了“， 你想练仙不成 ?
Excuse me
装宴
Can l help you?
什么事 ?
1d like to try this stereo
汽什么，我想试过人台机子
Ksitigarbha Sutral:
地藏著蔷本听经和谷上 :
"Pecple of the like shall be cast
into the Avinci Hell
「如是等理，当了距无间地洗
and Willl continue to suffer from Kalpas to Kalpas
With no means of escape."
二万俺劫，以此连物，求出扰期。j